<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thiago Araujo</title>
    <link>https://thraraujo.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thiago Araujo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thraraujo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cinemática em 2D &amp; 3D</title>
      <link>https://thraraujo.github.io/notes/01-cinematica/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thraraujo.github.io/notes/01-cinematica/</guid>
      <description>Cinemática em 2D e 3D Link to heading Introdução Link to heading O estudo do movimento e de suas causa é um dos principais temas da ciência, desde sua origem. Embora toda separação na ciência seja puramente pedagógica (e portanto artificial), podemos separar o estudo do movimento em dois campos: Cinemática e Dinâmica. Em linhas gerais, a Cinemática lida com os movimentos em si, as trajetórias que os corpos seguem, sua velocidade, sua aceleração.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leis de Newton</title>
      <link>https://thraraujo.github.io/notes/02-leis-de-newton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thraraujo.github.io/notes/02-leis-de-newton/</guid>
      <description>Leis de Newton Link to heading Introdução Link to heading As 3 leis de Newton formam o pilar da física moderna, e não seria um exagero afirmar que de toda a ciência moderna. É difícil pensar numa área da ciência que não tenha sido influenciada pelo desenvolvimento posterior da mecância Newtoniana. A &amp;quot;termo-dinâmica&amp;quot;, que hoje falamos termodinâmica, que está por trás da primeira revolução indrustrial; todo o desenvolvimento da eletrônica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website with Hugo is a breeze</title>
      <link>https://thraraujo.github.io/posts/create_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thraraujo.github.io/posts/create_website/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this post is twofold. First I want to help other people to build their static website without spending two important resources: time and money. Also, it is an explanation to my future self &amp;ndash; as Damian Conway said:
&amp;ldquo;Documentation is a love letter that you write to your future self”
So, let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
Hugo Link to heading Hugo is the framework we use to build our website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://thraraujo.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thraraujo.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a theoretical physicist currently working at the Institute for Theoretical Physics, UNESP, as a postdoc. My research interests span topics in integrable systems and applications in statistical physics and string theory.
Short CV Link to heading 2023 - Present : Postdoc at the São Paulo State University, Brazil 2023 - 2023 : Postdoc at the University of São Paulo, Brazil 2022 - 2023 : Lecturer at the Federal University of Alagoas, Brazil 2019 - 2021 : Postdoc at the University of Bern, Switzerland 2016 - 2019 : Postdoc at the Asia Pacific Center for Theoretical Physics, South Korea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sobre</title>
      <link>https://thraraujo.github.io/_about.pt-br/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thraraujo.github.io/_about.pt-br/</guid>
      <description>Sou um físico teórico atualmente trabalhando no Instituto de Física Teórica, Unesp. Minha interesse de pesquisa abrange tópicos em modelos integráveis e aplicações em física estatística e teoria de cordas.
Breve CV Link to heading 2023 - Presente : Postdoc na Universidade Estadual Paulista, São Paulo 2023 - 2033 : Postdoc na Universidade de São Paulo, Brasil 2023 - 2023 : Postdoc at the University of São Paulo, Brasil 2022 - 2023 : Professor substituto na Universidade Federal de Alagoas, Brasil 2019 - 2021 : Postdoc na Universidade de Berna, Suíça 2016 - 2019 : Postdoc no Asia Pacific Center for Theoretical Physics, Coréia do Sul 2012 - 2016 : Doutorado na Universidade Estadual Paulista, São Paulo </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Cheatsheet I : Basics</title>
      <link>https://thraraujo.github.io/posts/vim_cheatsheet_i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thraraujo.github.io/posts/vim_cheatsheet_i/</guid>
      <description>Vim Cheatsheet: Basics Link to heading Let us start with the notation:
C-a = Ctrl-a Getting Started Link to heading vim &amp;lt;file&amp;gt; Open file. vim &amp;lt;file1&amp;gt; &amp;lt;file2&amp;gt; Open file1 and file2 vim -R &amp;lt;file&amp;gt; Open file in read mode view &amp;lt;file&amp;gt; Open file in read mode :h[elp] &amp;lt;keyword&amp;gt; Open help for the keyword :term Open a terminal :! &amp;lt;cmd&amp;gt; Execute shell command &amp;lt;cmd&amp;gt; &amp;lt;C-\&amp;gt;&amp;lt;C-n&amp;gt; Go to command mode in the built-in terminal ESC Exit insert mode :q Close document if no modification has been done :w Save the document :wa Save all windows :wq Save and close :x Save and close, equivalent to wq :q!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Cheatsheet II : Beyond the Basics</title>
      <link>https://thraraujo.github.io/posts/vim_cheatsheet_ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thraraujo.github.io/posts/vim_cheatsheet_ii/</guid>
      <description>Vim Cheatsheet: Beyond the Basics Link to heading Registers Link to heading When we delete something with vim, the previous 9 deletions are saved in an unnamed register. We can access these registers with numbers from 1 to 9. For example:
&amp;#34;nP Paste the register n, n from 1 to 9, before the cursor &amp;#34;np Paste the register n, n from 1 to 9, after the cursor On the other hand, one can use named registers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pesquisa</title>
      <link>https://thraraujo.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thraraujo.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Interesses Link to heading Meus interesses de pesquisa são:
2018 &amp;ndash; Presente : Integrabilidade e análise combinatória em teorias de cordas e física estatística 2016 - 2018 : Holografia em espaços planos, deformações integráveis de supergravidade 2010 - 2017 : Teorias de campos conformes e integráveis, correspondência AdS/CFT e teoria de cordas Publicações Link to heading Todos os meus artigos estão disponíveis online: Inspire-HEP e arXiv.
T. Araujo, “Q-Boson model and relations with integrable hierarchies,&amp;quot; 2405.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://thraraujo.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thraraujo.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Interests Link to heading My research interests are the following:
2018 &amp;ndash; Present : Integrability and combinatorics in string theory and in statistical physics 2016 - 2018 : Flat space holography, integrable deformations of supergravity 2010 - 2017 : Integrable and conformal field theories, AdS/CFT, string theory Publications Link to heading All my papers are available online: Inspire-HEP and arXiv.
T. Araujo, “Q-Boson model and relations with integrable hierarchies,&amp;quot; 2405.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
